Trisha Stamm

Data Scientist, Microsoft Certified

Phone 401-439-3501

LinkedIn linkedin.com/in/trishastamm

E-mail trishastamm@gmail.com

Microsoft and Google certified data scientist with 9 years of experience. Seeking to increase data efficiency for Contranix, Inc. Achievements include creating models to predict stock price with 25% more accuracy than the historical average. Achieved 20% improvement in investment returns.



Experience

2013-10 -2017-12 **Data Scientist**

- Exend Capital Inc.
- · Fulfilled all data science duties for a high-end capital management firm.
- · Created and presented models for potential holdings to fund managers. Achieved 20% better returns vs historical performance.
- · Predicted stock price 25% better than traditional figures.

2012-08 -

Junior Data Scientist

2013-09

Supracy Real Estate Inc.

- · Collaborated with all team members to optimize Customer Relationship Management database for a high-volume real estate firm.
- · Increased repeat business among real estate investors by 25%.

2012-06 -2017-12

Freelance Data Scientist

Various

- NCAAMaster: Beat 200+ statistics professors, students, and professionals in an NCAA pool. Didn't try to cram basketball into a framework where it didn't fit.
- · FootForest: Used random forest regressor to predict fantasy football scores.



Education

2008 2012

BS in Statistics, Syracuse University

- · Excelled in machine learning and data science coursework.
- · Completed a senior project to predict waitress tips in a busy Boston restaurant. Used decision trees, regression models, and SVM.

Microsoft Professional Program for Data Science

· Completed all 10 required courses in Data Science (120 hours).

*

Additional Activities

Problem Solving

- · Article "Machine Learning in the Next 10 Years" cited in Forbes.
- · Volunteer monthly at the Boylston St. Soup Kitchen.



Soft Skills

		Experi
	Critical Thinking	
	Creative Thinking	Exper
Ţ	Hard Skills	Exper
	R Studio, Python, PERL, NoSQL, Hadoop, VB, Cloudera	
	Machine Learning	Exper
	Data Visualization	Exper
	Modeling	Exper
	Statistics	Experi
		Exper



Certifications

Microsoft Professional Program Certificate in Data Science

GCP - Google Certified Professional Data Engineer



Conferences